<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <info>
    <author>
       <personname>
          <firstname></firstname>
          <surname></surname>
       </personname>
       <email></email>
    </author>
    <abstract><wysiwyg_a><p>This function block is an extremely powerful tool. It enables various sorts of bit-manipulation in all directions.</p><p>It is a generic block. The number of inputs and outputs can be chosen independently from 1 to 32.</p><p>Pulling the symbol in the bottom right corner of the block up or down changes the number of either inputs or outputs. To change from input-alteration to output-alteration or conversely, just click the symbol in the bottom right corner of the block by a right-click and then choose INCNT or OUTCNT. Afterwards you can alter the selected ports by pulling with left-click again. </p><p>(More information about generic blocks: Studio help (press F1) at Solution→Distributed PAC Project→Editors→System Editor)</p><p /><p>
  </p></wysiwyg_a></abstract>
  </info>
<wysiwyg><p>
    <strong>Temporal Behavior</strong> </p><p>Each triggered 'INIT' initiates a check of input 'OP'. Only if the definition corresponds with the number of inputs this event leads to output 'STATUS' ok, otherwise it leads to an error report and the normal 'REQ' doesn't work.</p><p>If 'INIT' leads to 'STATUS' ok, each triggered 'REQ' executes the internal logic and leads to an 'CNF'-Event.</p><p>After each change of input 'OP' it is necessary to trigger 'INIT' before executing 'REQ'.</p><strong>
<div class="tip" style="HEIGHT: 84px; WIDTH: 990px; MARGIN-LEFT: 0.5in; MARGIN-RIGHT: 0.5in">
<table border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" rowspan="2" width="25" align="center"><img alt="[tip]" src="file:///C:/Program%20Files/nxtControl/nxtControl-1.5/Studio/data/docbook-5.0/docbook-xsl-1.74.0/nxtControl/Images/tip.png" /></td>
<th align="left">If Output STATUS always leads to an error report:</th></tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<p>Check your input definitions of OP. The number of output information has to be less or equal to the number of input information.</p></td></tr></tbody></table></div></strong><p> </p><p><strong>Functional Behavior</strong></p><p>Input 'OP' defines the functionality of all outputs ('OUT1' ... 'OUTn'). Possible are 32 inputs and 32 outputs as maximum. They can be BOOL, BYTE, WORD, DWORD, LWORD-type.</p><p>All inputs together are to be looked upon as one whole bit-image, whereas bit 0 is lsb (least significant bit) of the first input. Highest bit is msb (most significant bit) of the last input. The same order is true for output. [i.e. input1 is BYTE, input2 is BOOL, input3 is BYTE then first output address 0 (LSB of 1.BYTE) -7 (MSB of 1.Byte), then 8 (BOOL), and 9 (LSB of 2.BYTE) - 16 (MSB of 2.Byte)].</p><p>There is the possibility to set the starting position for the output bit (e.g. 3=1 means: output bit 3 = input bit 1), but it's optional. If not, starting position is 0, respectively the position where the last operation has finished. Further actions join on the next output bit position.</p><ul>
<li>n, or n-m, or m-n, takes the bit number n from input to the next output position, whereby m-n will reverse the order. </li>
<li>n:i, n-m:i, m-n:i, same as above, but with invert value. </li>
<li>n:0 number of n 0-bits from the next output position. </li>
<li>n:1 number of n 1-bits from the next output position. </li>
<li>Not defined output bits are 0. </li>
<li>OP completely blank has the same meaning than 0-n.</li></ul><p><u>Examples:</u></p><p>Endianness-alteration of a DWORD:</p><p>24-31,16-23,8-15,0-7</p><p>Third bit to output position 0 (=lsb of output1), second to position 8 invert, the third and fourth bit in reversed order on output position 9 and 10, and beginning with position 16 eight times 1: </p><p>2,8=1:i,4-3,16=8:1</p><p>To split a BYTE from one input in reversed order to 8 BOOL-outputs:</p><p>7-0</p><p>
</p><p /><p>
  </p></wysiwyg></section>
