<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <info>
    <author>
       <personname>
          <firstname></firstname>
          <surname></surname>
       </personname>
       <email></email>
    </author>
    <abstract><wysiwyg_a><p>This function block is the bus master using a standardized DLL as the underlying driver.</p><p /><p>
  </p></wysiwyg_a></abstract>
  </info>
<wysiwyg><p>This function block provides the bus master using a standardized DLL as the underlying driver. The DLL contains all operations needed to initialize, start, run, stop and uninitialize the driver. The CONFIGURATION input is used to pass all the information necessary to configure the driver instance - for simple drivers this can be a configuration string, for more complicated ones it can be name of the configuration file.</p><p>The DLL_NAME parameter contains a name of the DLL to load. The DLL is searched according to the dlopen() semantics.</p><p>The OPS_NAME contains a name of the symbol inside the DLL providing the operations structure. Consult the manual for the particular driver to find its value.</p><p>Usually there can be only one instance of BM_DLL for every DLL_NAME / OPS_NAME combination. This is not enforced by the FB.</p><p> </p><div class="caution" style="MARGIN-LEFT: 0.5in; MARGIN-RIGHT: 0.5in">
<table border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" rowspan="2" width="25" align="center"><img alt="[caution]" src="${DocImages}/caution.png" /></td>
<th align="left">Caution</th></tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<p>By using a dynamically loaded code you are operating in the memory space of the runtime. Any bugs, memory leaks, multithreading problems, non-deterministic or inappropriately high delays have direct effect on the runtime and can cause its crash or incorrect operation.</p></td></tr></tbody></table></div><p>
  </p></wysiwyg></section>

