<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <info>
    <author>
       <personname>
          <firstname></firstname>
          <surname></surname>
       </personname>
       <email></email>
    </author>
    <abstract><wysiwyg_a><p>This function block generates single events at each of the event outputs where the number of events and the interval between each event is configurable. </p><p> </p><p>
</p><p /><p>
</p><p /><p>
  </p></wysiwyg_a></abstract>
  </info>
<wysiwyg><strong>
<div class="img">Temporal Behavior</div></strong><p>'START'-Event input: When a 'START'-Event arrives, the values of the 'N'-input and the 'DT'-input are read, then one output event at 'EO[0]' is produced after period TIME[0]. The next event is fired at EO[1] after TIME[1] period. And so on, until 'N' event outputs have been fired. </p><p><em>Please note:</em> If a new 'START'-Event arrives before the set of events has been fired entirely, the function block will start up again from the beginning. Events that have not been fired within the last period (because the time between the two 'Start'-Events was to short) will be discarded.</p><p><em>Please note:</em> The maximum number of event outputs is implementation dependent.</p><p>'STOP'-Event input: The event generation can be stopped by the 'STOP-Event input. A 'STOP'-Event is ignored when there was no 'START'-Event before.</p><p>Then a subsequent 'START'-Event can trigger a new set of output events. </p><p> </p><p><strong>Functional Behavior</strong></p><p>'DT'-input: The 'DT'-input value is interpreted as an array of the IEC-TIME duration format, for example: "[t#1s,t#20ms,t#4s]". The maximum number of entries is equal to the number of Event outputs of the function block.</p><p>'N'-input: Defines the number of events to generate. If the value of the 'N'-input is larger than the number of Event outputs of the function block 'N' will be truncated, if it is smaller than the number of entries in the list of 'DT', only the first entries (as much as N) will work. The remaining entries are ignored.</p><p><em>Please note:</em> <u>'N' must not be larger than the 'DT'-array is</u>. The time for generating events that are not parameterized at 'DT' is not defined, but the events will be fired anyway.</p><p>
</p><p /><p>
</p><p /><p>
  </p></wysiwyg></section>

