<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <info>
    <author>
       <personname>
          <firstname></firstname>
          <surname></surname>
       </personname>
       <email></email>
    </author>
    <abstract><wysiwyg_a><p>This function block generates events whereby the number of events and the interval between each event is configurable. </p><p><em /> </p><p>
  </p></wysiwyg_a></abstract>
  </info>
<wysiwyg><p>
    <strong>Temporal Behavior</strong> </p><p>The number of events is defined by the 'N'-input and the time interval between the output events is given by the time array set on 'DT'-input.</p><p>When a 'START'-Event is detected, the values of the 'N'-input and the 'DT'-input are read, then an output event at 'EO' is produced after a period TIME[0]. The 'CV'-output is set to '0' which is the current event index. The next event is produced after a period TIME[1]. 'CV' is set to '1'. And so on, until the number of events fired at 'EO' matches the value of 'N'. </p><p>The event generation can be stopped by the 'STOP-Event input. A 'STOP'-Event is ignored when there was no 'START'-Event before.</p><p>Then a subsequent 'START'-Event can trigger a new set of output events. </p><p><em>Please note:</em> If a new 'START'-Event arrives before the set of events has been fired entirely, the function block will start up again from the beginning. Events that have not been fired within the last period (because the time between the two 'Start'-Events was to short) will be discarded.</p><p> </p><p><strong>Functional Behavior</strong></p><p>'DT'-input: The 'DT'-input value is interpreted as an array of the IEC-TIME duration format, for example: "[t#5s,t#120ms,t#4s]". The maximum number of entries is emplementation dependent (standard is 16). </p><p>If the value of the 'N'-input is larger then the number of entries in the list of 'DT' then 'N' will be truncated.</p><p>'N'-input: Defines the number of events to generate. If the value of the 'N'-input is larger than the number of Events allowed (implementation dependent) 'N' will be truncated, if it is smaller than the number of entries in the list of 'DT', only the first entries (as much as N) will work. The remaining entries are ignored.</p><p><em>Please note:</em> <u>'N' must not be larger than the 'DT'-array is</u>. The time for generating events that are not parameterized at 'DT' is not defined, but the events will be fired anyway.</p><p> </p><p>
  </p></wysiwyg></section>

